# LEON ZHANG

(514)998-2475

leonzhang51@gmail.com

Montréal, Quebec

https://leonzhang51.github.io/

#### ABOUT ME

A designer who can code focused on both customer and business needs. Champions client ideas and produces solutions for development and product design that meet revenue goals.

- "How it Works" Focus: Adept at conceptualizing design ideas and bringing them to life with a focus on analysis, business requirements, and optimizing user experience.
- Innovative Thinker: Sees the big picture and provides creative, unique solutions for customers, with the goal of engaging users and earning their repeat visits.
- Business Results: Successful history of creating apps, landing pages, and new components that significantly increase traffic and revenue.

### DESIGN&CODE

#### **DESIGN** (6 years)

- User Centered Design
- UI Design & Graphic Design
- Rapid Prototyping & Wireframes
- User Research, Interview, Surveys
- Experience Strategy & Experience Map
- Responsive Web Design
- Business Design
- Sketch, Figma & Axure

#### CODE

- HTML 5/ CSS3/ JS/Bootstrap/jQuery (5 years)
- React/Angular/NodeJS/GIT/MVC/REST(2 year)
- PHP / MYSQL (3 years)
- Agile Methodology & SCRUM (4 years)

#### EDUCATION

**AEC Conception et programmation de sites Web** Collège de Maisonneuve | 2018 - 2019

**Bachelor's in Telecommunications Engineering**University of Electronic Science and Technology of China

#### EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS

### Bovana, Montréal, Quebec UX Engineer, 04 / 2020 - Present

Work to improve collaboration and communication between the design team and the engineering teams. Collaborate with researchers, designers, and developers to create concepts, iterate, and user-test a product, website, or application. Make sure a product or system is user-friendly, fully functional, and provides the required experience for the user.

- Communicating scenarios, end-to-end experiences, interaction models, mock-ups, and prototypes with other members of the team that clearly illustrate how application function and look.
- Work side-by-side with product designers to ideate on concepts and determine how to bring those designs to life.
- Design and build the front-end of web applications using HTML, CSS/SCSS, and JavaScript with a focus on user experience, inclusive design, and accessibility.
- Evaluating existing applications and their UX effectiveness and identify optimizations/solutions.
- Under development: Collaborated with UX designer and web developer to design and build beats sell online website by React JS, SCSS, Express, and Mongo DB.

## ChefAide, Montréal, Québec UX Designer/Web Developer, 06 / 2019 – 03 / 2020

Collaborated with team on implementing new features and UX in an agile environment, Coded the whole website using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, PHP, and MySQL.

Under development (2 projects): Creating website for Sireta
 OnDemand and Sireta Travel that estimates indicate will result in new employment opportunities as well as \$2M in increased company revenue.

## L3 Studio, Montreal, Quebec UX Designer/Frontend Developer, 02 / 2014 – 4/2018

Redesigned client websites, translating concepts and business requirements into user flows, wireframes, mock-ups, and prototypes to create an intuitive user experience.

- Implemented websites, mobile applications, and landing pages from concept through deployment.
- Produced stunning visual elements of web applications by translating UI/UX design wireframes into code while producing high quality, reusable markup using HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JQUERY, REACT, ANGULAR.
- Redesigned an online grocery store website, which resulted in a 46 percent increase in new user registrations and a 51 percent increase in repeat visits/purchases successfully increasing revenue by 120 percent.
- Added a new business model component to an online art store resulting in 100 percent growth of new users and a 300 percent increase in revenue in the first year.
- Boosted registration of new users by 40 percent with the introduction of a new display-result model that incorporated more meaningful, precise, and friendly content.
- Optimized the user journey on a client's mobile app based on a "simplify" philosophy, which increased customer satisfaction by 70 percent.